(綱手)何だ？ どうした？
What?
What happened?!
(シズネ)お待ちください
今 取り替えますから。
Please wait a minute.
I'll replace it right now.
すまん。
綱手様は まだ こちらに？
Thanks.
Lady Tsunade,
are you going to stay here?
あぁ もう少しな。
Yes, just a little longer.
お体に障りますから あまり
根をお詰めになりませんように。
It's not good for your health,
so please don't overdo it.
あ？ あぁ。
I know...
《自来也様渾身の作品ですものね。
Lord Jiraiya put his heart
and soul into this work...
夢中になるのも
無理ありませんね》
I don't blame her for
getting so absorbed in it.
"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
The Child of Prophecy
Hmm... A fourth tail?!
《自来也 : ４本目まで…。
I guess it was still too soon
まだ ナルトに
九尾チャクラのコントロールは➡
for Naruto to be able to control
the Nine Tails' Chakra...
無理だったか…》
I have no choice but to lock
the Eight Signed Seal once more.
SUPPRESS
《もう一度 八卦封印の鍵を➡
閉じるしかあるまいのぉ》
Naruto...
ナルト… 少しの間
おとなしくしているんだぞ。
Stay quiet just for a little while.
Art of the Raging Lion's Mane!
《乱獅子髪の術！》
SUPPRESS
I think I broke a few ribs.
くっ… あばらが 数本
いってしまったようじゃのぉ。
Summoning:
Bring Down the House Jutsu!
口寄せ 屋台崩しの術！
くっ…。
Earth Style: The Dark Swamp!
土遁 黄泉沼！
Naruto! Take back your self!
ナルト 自我を取り戻すんだ！
Naruto!
《ナルト…》
SAGE
Jiraiya-boy.
((フカサク : 自来也ちゃんよ。
The Great Lord Elder
had a dream about you.
(フカサク)大じじ様は
お前の夢を見られたんじゃ。
As you know, it is a prophecy.
お前も知ってのとおり
これは予言じゃ。
Listen closely.
心して聞け。
はい。
Yes, sir!
I shall now tell you...
(大ガマ仙人)では伝える。
In my dream,
you, who are solely pervy,
わしの夢では
エロいだけのおぬしも➡
will still manage to become
a splendid shinobi.
いずれ立派な忍になる。
And in time,
you will have your own disciples...
そして 一人前に何人もの
弟子を持つことになるのじゃが。
"Solely pervey"?
《エロいだけって…。
I can't believe he just
remembers that particular detail...
そういうことは
しっかり覚えてんだから》
One such disciple will come to
possess a great power.
(大ガマ仙人)その者は
何か強大な力を手にする者。
Depending on how you guide him,
その者をお前がどう導くかで
忍社会の未来は大きく変わる。
the future of the Shinobi World
will undergo a great change.
I'm going to guide him?
私が導く？
Furthermore,
it is your disciple
しかも お前のその弟子が➡
who will influence the future of
the Shinobi World greatly.
忍社会の未来に
大きく関わることになるようじゃ。
My disciple is?
私の弟子が… ですか？
Yes...
うむ… 忍世界の未来には➡
The future of the Shinobi World will
be wrought with many calamities.
さまざまな災厄が降り注ぐ。
And one of your disciples
そして
お前の弟子のなかの１人が➡
will be the one who will
cast away those calamities.
その災厄を祓っていくじゃろう。
However...
じゃが…。
よき方向に導けば
よき世界に変わり➡
If they are guided
in the right direction,
the world will change for the good.
悪しき方向へ導けば
破滅をもたらす。
If they are guided
in the wrong direction,
they will bring about great ruin.
You are the one who will
guide the Child of Prophecy
おぬしは その予言の子を
よき方向に導く➡
水先案内人の役割を
なさねばならない…。
in the right direction.
The Child of Prophecy?
(予言の子？))
Impossible...
《まさか 破滅をもたらすのは…》
To think the one who might
bring about great ruin is—?!
Do you all plan on ignoring
the rules of the village?
(サスケ)お前たち 里の掟を
守らないつもりか？
Yeah.
(シカマル)ああ。 捕まった仲間たちを
見捨てて➡
We can't return to the village
when our friends are
being held captive.
里へ帰ることはできない。
それが 俺たち全員の意志だ。
We all agree on that.
((フガク : ハァ… やはり
イタチの時のようにはいかんか。
Why did I think
you would be like Itachi?
Perhaps it's still too soon for you.
お前には まだ
早すぎたのかもしれんな。
Sasuke...
サスケよ。
イタチは 同じ年頃には
完璧にできていたぞ。
Itachi was able to perfectly master it
when he was about your age.
And currently, Itachi has been
appointed to the ANBU,
そして 今は 火影様の
直属の暗部に任命された。
under Lord Hokage's
direct supervision.
The Leaf Police Force upholds
the laws of the village...
里の掟を守らねばならない
木ノ葉の警務部隊としては➡
and I was hoping to fill the void
left by Itachi's transfer...
イタチの抜けた穴を 今すぐにでも
埋めたかったのだがな。
Focus!
(精進しろ))
I won't lose to Big Brother!
《兄さんには負けない。
To honor the rules,
I'll destroy the puppets!
掟を守るためには
傀儡を突破する！》
I see... A smokescreen...
(ヒルコ)なるほど 目くらましか…。
Sasuke!
(サクラ)サスケ君！
He created a blind spot
for the puppet user!
煙玉で 傀儡使いの
死角を作ったのか？
That was so reckless!
(キバ)無茶な真似を！
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
火遁 豪火球の術！
So I guess it won't be that easy...
《やはり 簡単にはいかないか！》
(リー)うお～！
Even if our goals differ,
we can't ignore our friends!
たとえ 目的は違っても➡
仲間を
放っておくわけにはいきません！
Everyone, follow Lee!
チッ！ みんな リーに続け！
Human Boulder!
Roll! Roll! Roll!
(チョウジ)肉弾戦車！ ゴロゴロゴロ…。
Shannaro!
しゃ～んなろ～!!
Fang Over Fang!
牙通牙！
(ヒナタ)はっ！
Sasuke!
サスケ！ まさか
俺たちが お前のことを➡
I hope you didn't charge at
the puppets by yourself,
見捨てられないのわかってて➡
because you knew full well that
we don't leave our friends behind...
単身 傀儡に向かったわけじゃ
ねえだろうな？
フンッ…。
They attacked the puppets...
(小南)全員で あの傀儡たちに…。
Do they intend on
bringing down the puppets,
(弥彦)彼らは 傀儡を突破して
木ノ葉の里へ戻るつもりか？
and then return to Leaf Village?
Did they choose the rules
over their friends?
仲間を助けることより
掟を守るほうを選んだのか。
Even the young ones cannot
break free of the curse of rules.
若いやつらでも 掟の呪縛からは
解き放たれないのか。
After all, a caged bird is a caged bird.
やはり かごの鳥はかごの鳥。
They don't know how to fly freely
through the heavens.
自由に天空を飛ぶことは
かなわぬのか…。
Has your Byakugan become cloudy?
(ネジ)あなたの白眼は
曇ってしまったのですか？
What?!
なに!?
They're not fighting because
they want to honor the rules...
彼らは 掟を守るためではなく➡
They're fighting for their friend.
仲間のために動いたんだ。
They're not bound by the rules...
掟に縛られてではなく
自分自身の意志で➡
By their own will, they're fighting
to save their friend.
仲間を助けるために
戦っているんだ。
I guess this is far enough.
(ヒルコ)もういいだろう
これがやつらの結論だ。
They've already decided.
It's pretty obvious...
わかってたことじゃねえか。
There's no future for shinobi.
忍に未来なんかねえ。
There is only... hell.
あるのは 地獄。
Let me show you an artistic
and eternal hell!
芸術的なまでの永遠の地獄を
見せてやる！
Damn it! He had spare puppets!
しまった！ 予備の傀儡も
持ってやがったのか！
(ナルト)ぐっ… うぅ…。
You said there are three steps
in the training... right, Dad?
((修業は 第三段階まであんだろ？
父ちゃん。
You've only taught me two.
まだ第二段階までしか
教えてもらってねえってばよ。
That's right.
(ミナト)そうだったね。
Now then...
さあ。
えっ これってば ただの風船だろ。
This is an ordinary balloon.
The first step is rotation.
(ミナト)第一段階は回転
第二段階は威力。
The second step is force.
I'm able to do up to there.
そこまではできたってば。
And the third step is...
そして 第三段階は➡
The one in my right palm
looks like an ordinary balloon, right?
左の手のひらにのっているのは
普通の風船に見えるよね？
Y-Yeah...
えっ うん。
If you reproduce the contents of
the balloon with your right hand...
その風船の中身を
右手で再現すると…。
Amazing!
Massive chakra revolves erratically...
and it goes faster and faster...
すっげえ！ チャクラが乱回転して
どんどん速くなってるのに➡
But the balloon remains
perfectly round.
風船は きれいに
まん丸のままだ。
Namely, the chakra in the second step
which was infused with force,
つまり 第二段階で
威力を高めたチャクラを➡
is fixed inside the balloon.
風船の中にとどめる。
"Fixed"?
えっ とどめる？
As you put force into the chakra,
you compress it and fix it.
威力を高めながら
圧縮してとどめるんだ。
Huh?!
え～!?
ただでさえ両手を使って➡
It's hard enough making it turn and
adding force with both hands!
回転と威力で 精一杯なのに➡
You can increase it even more?!
これ以上 まだ増えんのかよ～。
アッハハハ！
猫の手も借りたいところかな？
I guess you could use all
the extra help you can get!
But if you can do this...
でも これができれば…。
Whoa! Awesome!
うわ… すっげえ。
This Rasengan is
a super high-level ninjutsu.
超高等忍術の螺旋丸だよ。
Only two shinobi can do this:
Jiraiya Sensei and I.
これができるのは
僕と自来也先生だけなんだ。
Do you think I'll be able to do it too?
あのさ 俺にも
できるようになんのかな？
Yeah! I'm sure you will!
(ああ キミならきっとね))
Oh yeah...
"all the extra help, I can get."
《そうか 猫の手…》
Damn it!
クソ！
What's going on?
どうなってるの？ これ。
きりがありません。
There's no end to this in sight!
クッ…。
《サクラちゃん！》
Sakura!
Wait!
《待ってて
今 助けに行くってばよ！》
I'm coming to save you!
Naruto?!
ナルト!?
うぉ～！
うっ うぅ…。
Pervy Sage?!
エロ仙人？
おぉ 戻ってきたか。
You're back.
How did you get hurt?!
そのケガ どうしたんだってばよ!?
It's nothing, don't worry.
心配するな。
But I can't move,
so I'm going back for now.
だが わしは動けぬから
いったん戻る。
So you'd better get back
to the others.
だから お前は
早く皆のもとへ行ってやれのう。
Reverse Summoning Jutsu!
逆口寄せの術！
う… ん？
What, what?!
えっ えっ えっ… あぁ！
Ouch!
イテテ…。
あっ。
This isn't good.
At this rate, they'll be...
まずい このままじゃあいつらが。
– Wait!
– But?!
(長門)待て。
しかし。
The way things are going,
the Hidden Leaf shinobi are in danger.
このままでは
木ノ葉の忍たちが危ない。
No...
I sense massive chakra...
いや 何か大きなチャクラを感じる。
Why did this turn into such a drag?
I'm such an idiot!
なんで こんな
めんどくせえことに。
バカだぜ 俺は。
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身の術！
Rotation! Force!
回転 威力 もう一人が猫の手だ。
And with some "extra help,"
I can fix it!
これで留める！
What is that?!
(いの)何なの？ あれ。
なんてチャクラだ。
Look at the chakra!
That jutsu...
It's the Rasengan!
あの術… 螺旋丸だ。
Impossible!
That's because that jutsu is...
(シノ)ありえない…
なぜなら あの術は…。
Naruto's amazing!
(ヒナタ)すごい ナルト君。
Naruto!
ナルト…。
Here I go!
いくぞ～！
Rasengan!
螺旋丸！
うお～！
てや～！
What?!
なに…。
Next one...
Let's go!
次！ いくぞ！
おう！
Here we go!
うお～！
いくぜ！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身の術！
Naruto?!
ナルト!?
Damn you...
You ruined my art!
貴様 俺の芸術を
台なしにしやがって。
Are you the Puppet User?!
お前が傀儡使いか。
チッ。
うわっ！
あっ しまった。
Damn it!
He got away...
逃げられちまったってばよ。
That was amazing, Naruto!
すごい ナルト！
Taking down all those puppets,
by yourself.
あれだけの傀儡を
１人で倒しちまうなんて。
I think I might have
underestimated you all this time.
今まで ナルト君のことを
見誤っていたかもしれません。
Yeah!
You were hiding some amazing power!
(テンテン)えぇ
すごい力 隠してたのね。
That power has to be acknowledged.
その実力は
認めざるを得ない。
That's because, everyone had
a tough time with the enemy,
なぜなら
皆が苦戦していた敵を➡
but you came and
took them down by yourself.
１人で倒してしまったのは
事実だからだ。
As one would expect of Naruto!
うん さすがナルト君。
I was totally surprised!
ほんと ビックリしちゃった。
They say skilled hawks
hide their talons...
能ある鷹は爪を隠すって言うけど。
I hate to admit it,
but this is the one time
I have to acknowledge him.
悔しいが 今日ばっかは
認めねえわけにはいかねえな。
(赤丸)アン アン！
By the way, Naruto...
ところで ナルト
俺たちは仲間を助ける。
We're going to save our friends.
It will mean disobeying
the rules of the village...
里の掟に逆らうことにはなるが
それが俺たち みんなの意見だ。
But that's what we all want.
Yeah... Of course,
I feel the same way.
あぁ もちろん俺も
みんなと同じ気持だってばよ。
What will you do, Sasuke?!
どうする？ サスケ。
With this much fighting strength,
これだけの戦力があれば➡
you can't say rescuing
our friends is impossible.
仲間の救出作戦も
無謀だとは言えないはずだ。
Sasuke, come with us!
サスケ 一緒に来てくれってばよ。
Whatever.
勝手にしろ。
よし これで決まった！
All right! It's decided!
Everyone, you heard it!
We've joined up.
みんな 聞いたな？
俺たちは一致団結し
アスマたちを➡
We're going to rescue Asuma and...
no, we're going to find our friends
and rescue them!
仲間たちを見つけて
助け出す！
– All right!
(ナルトたち)よし！
Has your so-called test
produced a result?
あなたの言う
実験の結果は出ましたか？
I believe it's already been proven that
they consider the bonds of friendship
彼らは里の掟より➡
more important than
the rules of the village.
仲間どうしの絆を
大事にすることを➡
証明してくれたはずです。
So there's no need to
continue this test.
もう 実験をする必要は
ないでしょう。
You will release all the Hidden Leaf
Shinobi you've abducted, right?
今までさらった
木ノ葉の忍たち 全員を➡
返してくださいますね？
Father?
父上。
yumemiru toraburumeikaa
A dreaming troublemaker
hitori de dekiru furi o shite
Acting like he can do everything alone
furueru hiza o daite tsuyogatteru
Pretending to be strong
as he holds his shaking knees still
wagamama kogitsune fuaitaa
Spoiled fox cub fighter
hatenaga uzumaita sekai
In a world swirling with questions
mienai kizuna musunde hashitteku
He ties invisible bonds and keeps on running
mado kara tobasu kamihikouki sora aokute
A paper airplane hurled out of a window into the blue sky
anata ga naitekureta kara tsuyoku nareta no kana
You cried for me, Maybe that's why I grew strong
saa, yaru dake yattemiyou yo
Come on, let's do what we can
kore ga yume demo ii jan
So what if this is a dream?
senobi toka shichattemo ii janai? (oh)
It's okay to push ourselves to the limit, right? (Oh)
i wanna be with you
I  wanna  be  with  you
(go go) yurase emoushon
(Go go) Let your emotions go
(let's go) kitto daijoubu
(Let's go) It will be all right
(go go) aozora no hate made tobashiteyuke
(Go go) Let it fly to the farthest reaches of the blue sky
Who are you?
We are not your enemies.
<旬の小鉢が大好きな豆助>
First of all, we have to show you
a sign of mutual trust.
♪～
We apologize for
getting you involved
in the test that
our employer devised!
The test is over.
We'll release your friends.
≫豆助
Are you telling the truth?
きょうは 今が旬の
アレを使った小鉢よ
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Caged Bird"
< その小鉢とは…？>
You guys know Pervy Sage?
< それは…>